<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Recent Content on Notes by Alexey Diyan </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>https://diyan.github.io/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 02:49:05 EET</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two ways to setup all Python versions in Docker image</title>
      <link>https://diyan.github.io/posts/2015/all_pythons_in_docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 02:49:05 EET</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://diyan.github.io/posts/2015/all_pythons_in_docker/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m using Travis CI to run &lt;code&gt;pywinrm&lt;/code&gt; tests for different Python versions but only Python 2.7 is used for development at my workstation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be nice if all those tests could be executed locally by me or by contributors, so I did some analysis and sharing my results here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually it would be simple command like &lt;code&gt;make.sh test&lt;/code&gt; that will build Docker image and run all tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In most cases I&amp;rsquo;m prefer to use &lt;code&gt;debian:jessie&lt;/code&gt; because it&amp;rsquo;s a base for a majority of official images; but here I will go with Ubuntu image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Precompiled packages from Deadsnakes Ubuntu PPA&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image virtual size is 327 MB&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Dockerfile&#34;&gt;FROM ubuntu:14.04
MAINTAINER Alexey Diyan &amp;lt;alexey.diyan@gmail.com&amp;gt;

RUN set -x \
    &amp;amp;&amp;amp; pythonVersions=&#39;python2.6 python2.7 python3.1 python3.2 python3.3 python3.4 python3.5&#39; \
    &amp;amp;&amp;amp; apt-get update \
    &amp;amp;&amp;amp; apt-get install -y --no-install-recommends software-properties-common \
    &amp;amp;&amp;amp; apt-add-repository -y ppa:fkrull/deadsnakes \
    &amp;amp;&amp;amp; apt-get update \
    &amp;amp;&amp;amp; apt-get install -y --no-install-recommends $pythonVersions \
    &amp;amp;&amp;amp; apt-get purge -y --auto-remove software-properties-common \
    &amp;amp;&amp;amp; rm -rf /var/lib/apt/lists/*

CMD bash
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Compile from source using pyenv tool&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image virtual size is 1.034 GB&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Dockerfile&#34;&gt;FROM debian:jessie
MAINTAINER Alexey Diyan &amp;lt;alexey.diyan@gmail.com&amp;gt;

ENV PATH /root/.pyenv/shims:/root/.pyenv/bin:$PATH
RUN set -x \
    &amp;amp;&amp;amp; pythonVersions=&#39;2.6.9 2.7.10 3.1.5 3.2.6 3.3.6 3.4.3 3.5.0&#39; \
    &amp;amp;&amp;amp; buildDeps=&#39;ca-certificates curl git libjpeg-dev build-essential make libssl-dev zlib1g-dev libbz2-dev libreadline-dev libsqlite3-dev&#39; \
    &amp;amp;&amp;amp; apt-get update \
    &amp;amp;&amp;amp; apt-get install --no-install-recommends -y $buildDeps \
    &amp;amp;&amp;amp; curl -L https://raw.githubusercontent.com/yyuu/pyenv-installer/master/bin/pyenv-installer | bash \
    &amp;amp;&amp;amp; echo $pythonVersions | xargs -n 1 pyenv install \
    &amp;amp;&amp;amp; apt-get purge -y --auto-remove $buildDeps \
    &amp;amp;&amp;amp; rm -rf /var/lib/apt/lists/*

CMD bash

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;In addition..&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I have tried to build image based on &lt;code&gt;alpine:3.2&lt;/code&gt;, just for fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compilation did work for Python versions 2.7.10, 3.3.6, 3.4.3, 3.5.0 which is good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I have not managed to build following versions - 2.6.9, 3.1.5, 3.2.6; compilation was failed for both GCC and Clang compilers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Virtual DOM, FRP, Hyperscript</title>
      <link>https://diyan.github.io/posts/2015/js_virtual_dom_and_frp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 00:17:33 EET</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://diyan.github.io/posts/2015/js_virtual_dom_and_frp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the late 2014 I decided to take a look at bleeding edge JavaScript frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From time to time I&amp;rsquo;m hearing new buzzwords and maybe the most often was ReactJS, so I decided to take a short look on a few modern frameworks and libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It worth mention that one thing is really conserns we in ReactJS. It&amp;rsquo;s JSX - a mix of JavaScript and HTML, the new language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I was really happy to see a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dominictarr/hyperscript&#34;&gt;Hyperscript&lt;/a&gt; - nice JavaScript DSL for building HTML documents. It uses just regular JavaScript, no fancy additions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s clear what kind HTML it will produce and we have no issues with text editors, code analysers, parsers and other dev tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to be sure that Hyperscript would not isolate me in any way, so I&amp;rsquo;ve searched a number of libraries which covers all common use cases that you may encounter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npmjs.com/package/react-hyperscript&#34;&gt;react-hyperscript&lt;/a&gt; - to use Hyperscript syntax in ReactJS app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npmjs.com/package/virtual-dom-stringify&#34;&gt;virtual-dom-stringify&lt;/a&gt; - to turn a DOM node into a virtual-dom tree&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npmjs.com/package/vdom-virtualize&#34;&gt;vdom-virtualize&lt;/a&gt; - to turn a DOM node / HTML string into a virtual-dom tree&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npmjs.com/package/virtual-dom-jsx&#34;&gt;virtual-dom-jsx&lt;/a&gt; - transpiler from JSX to virtual-hyperscript code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npmjs.com/package/vtree-select&#34;&gt;vtree-select&lt;/a&gt; - to use CSS selector with virtual-dom nodes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully to ReactJS I&amp;rsquo;ve got familiar with Virtual DOM concept. Also I&amp;rsquo;m really glad that Facebook&amp;rsquo;s ReactJS moving forward popularity of Functional Reactive Programming (FRP) paradigm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most likely I could miss a number JavaScript libraries that exposes Virtual DOM and/or Hyperscript DSL but what I&amp;rsquo;ve found are following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Matt-Esch/virtual-dom/blob/master/virtual-hyperscript/README.md&#34;&gt;Virtual DOM&lt;/a&gt; - base library that provides Virtual DOM API and Hyperscript DSL for more high level frameworks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lhorie.github.io/mithril/index.html&#34;&gt;Mithril&lt;/a&gt; - IE6+, no deps, Virtual DOM concept. 2434 stars, 183 forks on GitHub&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Raynos/mercury&#34;&gt;Mercury&lt;/a&gt; -  IE9+, based on virtual-dom lib and observ-struct. FRP. 1128 stars, 49 forks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vuejs.org/&#34;&gt;VueJS&lt;/a&gt; - IE9+, MVVM, Virtual DOM concept. 3327 stars, 268 forks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/staltz/cycle&#34;&gt;CycleJS&lt;/a&gt; - browser compatibility unclear, based on virtual-dom and RxJS libs. FRP. 387 stars, 9 forks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mithrill looks attractive if you need a framework with minimal footprint, wide browser support and traditional approach for templating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time it&amp;rsquo;s data binding looks a bit weird. Not sure but this could be a trade off for deciding to support IE6 (and saying &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; to JavaScript getters/setters).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mercury is the most interesting framework for me. It contains a number of interesting concepts that I know in theory but eager to try in practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Raynos/mercury/blob/master/docs/modules/README.md&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; you can find a very good documentation that explains a lot implementation details, I would reccomend you pay attention on vdom-thunk, main-loop and time-travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In samples you can find an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Raynos/mercury/blob/2048-wip/examples/2048/state.js#L26-L34&#34;&gt;annoying&lt;/a&gt; mapping from plain JavaScript object to Mercury&amp;rsquo;s observ. Unfortunately this is something you have to deal with. I remember my happines when I saw how KnockoutJS opened FRP to the JavaScript world and then my sadness after I wrote a lot of boilerplate code that maps plain objects to observables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately there is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/maxogden/observify&#34;&gt;oservify&lt;/a&gt; - an automapper from plain JavaScript objects to Mercury&amp;rsquo;s observ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VueJS is a way to go if you need a Virtual DOM-powered version of AngularJS. This frameworks is rapidly gaining stars/forks on GitHub and soon we may see it in line with other top JavaScript frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CycleJS does not have too much popularity now and not likely it will. But author did a very important step - it included full-blown general purpose library RxJS that exposes all power of FRP / Reactive Programming to application framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end here is a link to &lt;a href=&#34;http://jsperf.com/angular-vs-knockout-vs-ember/401&#34;&gt;benchmark&lt;/a&gt; between popular JavaScript frameworks and hopefully you&amp;rsquo;ll see how Virtual DOM-based frameworks kicks ass to all others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thats all. Looking forward for your comments on Google+.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary of passed 2014 year</title>
      <link>https://diyan.github.io/posts/2015/summary_of_passed_2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 14:46:39 EET</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://diyan.github.io/posts/2015/summary_of_passed_2014/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;2014 year had passed and it would be nice to dump all things that I did that year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Major&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Very first year with 0 days usage of Windows&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No usage at home, no usage at work. For a long time I was very interested in Linux and Open Source. During my work in .NET ecosystem I have a strong feeling that Open Source libraries and tools fit best to my way of getting job done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In September 2011 I made a major shift from .NET/Windows to Python/Linux. I did spent 6 years on .NET platform and have not slightest doubts to do this big change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;From Ubuntu to Arch Linux&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For about one and a half year I&amp;rsquo;ve put a large amount of effort to learn main Ubuntu administration topics - coreutils, boot loaders, file systems, daemons, networking, logging, security, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In parallel, a lot of desktop environment were tried and changed - Unity, Gnome 2, KDE 4, XFCE, LXDE and eventually I ended up on a very lightweight tiling window manager - &lt;a href=&#34;https://i3wm.org/&#34;&gt;i3wm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those two things and also a willing to have bleeding edge software led me to Arch Linux which I have started to use at home starting from October 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Medium/Minor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other things are somewhat smaller, so I will just list them without any ordering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visited Crete and Thailand. I&amp;rsquo;m rather indifferent to traveling, but my wife is crazy about this. To make her happier I had to visit United Arab Emirates, Sri Lanka, Turkey, Poland, Czech Republic, Germany, Austria so far. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got B1/B2 USA Visa which will be valid for next 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Docker user&lt;/strong&gt; since v0.4. Using it for software evaluation, integration testing, setting up dev environment (including boot2docker on Mac OS for one my colleague). Planning to start use it in production this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Become an advocate for &lt;strong&gt;structured logging&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/structlog&#34;&gt;structlog&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://nxlog.org/&#34;&gt;nxlog&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://logstash.net/&#34;&gt;logstash&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.elasticsearch.org/overview/kibana/&#34;&gt;Kibana&lt;/a&gt; (Ruby version, then AngularJS). Now considering to change nxlog + Logstash into Mozilla&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://hekad.readthedocs.org/&#34;&gt;Heka&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Become a &lt;strong&gt;metrics junky&lt;/strong&gt; - our &lt;a href=&#34;http://graphite.wikidot.com/&#34;&gt;Graphite&lt;/a&gt; installation contains metrics from application (&lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/scales&#34;&gt;scales&lt;/a&gt; then &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/metrology&#34;&gt;metrology&lt;/a&gt;), Nagios (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/shawn-sterling/graphios&#34;&gt;graphios&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;a href=&#34;http://collectd.org/&#34;&gt;CollectD&lt;/a&gt;, Amazon CloudWatch (homegrown script). Now planning to switch from Graphite to &lt;a href=&#34;http://influxdb.org/&#34;&gt;InfluxDB&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://grafana.org/&#34;&gt;Grafana&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did learn how to write LSB compatible init.d scripts and then happily threw away &lt;a href=&#34;(http://refspecs.linuxbase.org/LSB_3.1.0/LSB-Core-generic/LSB-Core-generic/iniscrptact.html&#34;&gt;all&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;a href=&#34;http://refspecs.linuxbase.org/LSB_3.1.0/LSB-Core-generic/LSB-Core-generic/iniscrptfunc.html&#34;&gt;knowledge&lt;/a&gt; and learn &lt;a href=&#34;http://upstart.ubuntu.com/cookbook/&#34;&gt;Upstart&lt;/a&gt;. I would rather support two scripts for Upstart and SystemD instead of returning to the Middle Ages. Learning SystemD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Started track all configs for nginx, upstart, logrotate, gunicorn, uwsgi, heka, git deploy/develop hooks in Git repository next to code. They are deployed on each web node via post-update/post-merge git hooks. Hopefully I will start use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ansible.com/&#34;&gt;Ansible&lt;/a&gt; for that at some point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn Nginx a bit - compression, etags, satic file caching with and w/o expire validation, PAM/LDAP integration, ACLs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Invested some time to learn Golang, keeping most attention on a philosophy benind this language and ecosystem in general. Right now it&amp;rsquo;s mostly theoretical knowledge and hopefully this year I would start some project in Golang.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My chronic test-all-the-things infection became worse this year, so I&amp;rsquo;ve adopted couple practices:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;assert_json_equal function that displays unified diff along with AssertionError&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In memory Gevent-SocketIO server inspired on this &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/miguelgrinberg/Flask-SocketIO/blob/master/flask_socketio/test_client.py&#34;&gt;implementation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asked my teammate to develop in process RiakClientMock that supports get/set and 2i lookups (unfortunately, later we dropped that code due to switch on Cassandra)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Came up with _cassandra_process (build/start Docker container with real Cassandra node once per test session) and cassandra_mock (truncate all tables before each test function/method) py.test fixtures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started use in process &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/mockredispy&#34;&gt;mockredispy&lt;/a&gt; instead of real redis instance to speed up tests (unfortunately it does not emulate pub/sub but we are planning to change that)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluated approach with Dockerized Selenium Server with PhantomJS, SlimerJS, Firefox and Chrome for running frontend tests (planning to integrate that into dev our process in 2015)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start using a bunch of nice Python libraries/tools:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/itertoolz&#34;&gt;itertoolz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/jsonschema&#34;&gt;jsonschema&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/wsgicors&#34;&gt;wsgicors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/simpleflake&#34;&gt;simpleflake&lt;/a&gt; (instead of uuid4)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/suds-jurko/0.6&#34;&gt;suds-jurko&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/gevent-socketio&#34;&gt;gevent-socketio&lt;/a&gt; (not quite happy with it and PR with 4 fixed bugs still without any feedback)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/Flask-Principal&#34;&gt;flask_principal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/twilio&#34;&gt;twilio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/apns&#34;&gt;apns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/unicodecsv/0.9.4&#34;&gt;unicodecsv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/python-geoip&#34;&gt;python_geoip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/text-unidecode&#34;&gt;text-unidecode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://testutils.org/multi-mechanize/&#34;&gt;multi_mechanize&lt;/a&gt; (instead of &lt;a href=&#34;http://jmeter.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Apache JMeter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://locust.io/&#34;&gt;Locust&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/cqlengine&#34;&gt;cqlengine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did a release of &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/pywinrm&#34;&gt;pywinrm&lt;/a&gt; v0.0.3. My pesonal project is moving forward - I was happy to see a code contribution from about 7 developers. pywinrm has about 2000-2500 monthly downloads on PyPI and it was &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.ansible.com/intro_windows.html&#34;&gt;included&lt;/a&gt; into Ansible project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got acquainted with several Virtual DOM and/or FRP frameworks - &lt;a href=&#34;http://vuejs.org/&#34;&gt;VueJS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://facebook.github.io/react/&#34;&gt;ReactJS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://lhorie.github.io/mithril/&#34;&gt;Mithrill&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Raynos/mercury&#34;&gt;Mercury&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Matt-Esch/virtual-dom&#34;&gt;Virtual-DOM&lt;/a&gt;. I hate JavaScript but planning to write some code in ECMAScript 6 with one of those frameworks (most likely Mercury). Even if I&amp;rsquo;m pure backend developer I&amp;rsquo;m prefer keeping fresh skills in JavaScript at least on a very basic level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Used awesome &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.percona.com/software/percona-toolkit&#34;&gt;Percona Tookit&lt;/a&gt; (pt-archiver, pt-config-diff, pt-mysql-summary, pt-online-schema-change, pt-table-sync) for managing pretty big MySQL servers that contains about 600GB data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dived into a world of distributed databases/storages - &lt;a href=&#34;http://basho.com/riak/&#34;&gt;Riak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://cassandra.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Cassandra&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.couchbase.com/&#34;&gt;Couchbase&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://bigcouch.cloudant.com/&#34;&gt;BigCouch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://hadoop.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Hadoop&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://hbase.apache.org/&#34;&gt;HBase&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://speakerdeck.com/vanstee/convergent-replicated-data-types&#34;&gt;CRDT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CAP_theorem&#34;&gt;CAP theorem&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/um/people/lamport/pubs/lamport-paxos.pdf&#34;&gt;Paxos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://raftconsensus.github.io/&#34;&gt;Raft&lt;/a&gt; and all that staff. Most time I have spent with Riak, Cassandra but ended up with Cassandra for my current project. Also I did tried &lt;a href=&#34;http://prestodb.io/&#34;&gt;Presto&lt;/a&gt;/Cassandra and planning to work with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.elasticsearch.org/&#34;&gt;Elasticsearch&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://spark.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Spark&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;http://databricks.com/blog/2014/07/01/shark-spark-sql-hive-on-spark-and-the-future-of-sql-on-spark.html&#34;&gt;Shark&lt;/a&gt;/Cassandra, &lt;a href=&#34;https://spark.apache.org/sql/&#34;&gt;Spark SQL&lt;/a&gt;/Cassandra this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also I was involved into setting up &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pcisecuritystandards.org/security_standards/&#34;&gt;PCI DSS&lt;/a&gt; compliant environment. During that time I have learn a lot best practices on security/traceability/configration management/monitoring that could be applied to any project. Amout of resources that I&amp;rsquo;ve collected was pretty big, so I published everything on &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/diyan/c35c0574d200ac3a36eb&#34;&gt;Gist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014 was awesome year with a lot of interesting tasks and technical chalenges and I&amp;rsquo;m eager to try new things that will come in this 2015 year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(better later than never :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>